

# Sylvester Arikhan

### **Full-Stack Developer**

A Full-stack Web Developer building responsive web applications using the MERN stack, with several years of chemistry and web development experience. I am able to work both independently and as part of a team, and am willing to learn new skills.

Email: arikhansylvester@gmail.com

Address: Hinter der Stockmuhle 22, 09599 Freiberg.

**Phone:** 01633731957

**Link:** https://ambabasly.github.io/My-Portfolio/index.html

## **Experience**

Jun 2020 - Present Junior Developer (Intern)

LocaaTech Lagos Nigeria

- Contributeing in the development of web appsusing HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Working along with Senior Developers to solveprogramming tasks.
- Helping in handling workflow as we progress on development of applications.

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020 Working Student

Volkswagen Sachsen GmbH Sachsen

- Receiving deliveries of vehicle parts and preparing them for production line.
- Assembling parts ready to be fitted to vehicle.
- Shaping metal sheets that will make up frame of the vehicle.
- Fixing parts to the frame.

Dec 2014 - Jul 2017 Assistance Quality Control

**AKMA Engineering Nigeria Limited** Lagos

- Treatment of water and accessing taste and clarity of drinking water.
- Completed and processed paperwork and reports outlining proper and improper operations.
- Maintained excellent attendance record, consistently arriving to work on time.
- Managed quality assurance program, including on- site evaluations, internal audits, and customer surveys.

### **Education**

Mar 2021 - Oct 2021

### Full-Stack Developer

# Career Foundry Berlin

- Completed a 941 hour full stack development training program under the supervision of industry leading mentors and tutors.
- The project-based program is divided into 2 parts, Introduction to Front-End Development and Full-Stack Immersion.
- Studied and trained through a total of 7 achievements from 60 exercises and 7 projects

Oct 2010 - Oct 2014

#### Bachelor of Sciences

Ambrose Alli University Ekpoma/Nigeria

Languages

**English** 

Native

**German** Intermediate Skills

HTML5

React.js TDD CSS MongoDB JavScript ReactNative Node.js

Project Management

# **Projects**

A **(Pokedex)** web application, built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript that loads data from an external API and enables the viewing of data points in detail.

Building the server-side component of a **(movies web application)**. The web application provide users with access to information about different movies, directors, and genres. Users can sign up, update their personal information, and create a list of their favorite movies.

Using React to build the client-side for an application called **(myFlix)** based on its existing server-side code (REST API and database)

A **(MeetApp).** serverless PWA that can display and filter meetup events from the Google calender API. It is developed using Test-Drive-Development techniques to ensure a high test coverage rate.

A **(Chat App)** for mobile devices using React Native. The app provide users with a chat interface and options to share images and their location.

Using Angular to build the client-side for an application called **(myFlix)**, based on its existing server-side code (REST API and database), with supporting documentation.

### **Certifications & Courses**

Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP SAP)

Project Management Professional (PMP)

### **Residence Permit**

Angehöriger Art 10 rl 2004/38/EU. (Gainful employment allowed).